Guide to the Records of National Conference on Soviet Jewry, undated, 1949, 1954, 1956, 1958-1993 *I-181 and *I-181A
American Jewish Historical Society, Newton Centre, MA and New York, NY
- Part 1, Series IV: Organizations Correspondence, undated, 1966-1979; Boxes 13-29.
  - Noar Mizrachi (Noam), 1978 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - North American Jewish Students Network, 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - North American Jewish Youth Council, 1967-1969, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Northern California Lawyers Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Northern Neighbors, 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Opportunities Industrialization Centers of America, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - ORT (see also: Women's American ORT), 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Pioneer Women, 1973-1978 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Promoting Enduring Peace, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Rabbinical Assembly, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Rabbinical Council of America, 1973-1977 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Ramaz School (see also: Kehilath Jeshurun), 1974-1977 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Rav Tov Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Red Cross, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Religious Zionists of America, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Research Institute on Soviet Jewry, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Radio Liberty Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Student Activists for Soviet Jewry, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Student Struggle for Soviet Jewry, 1970-1978 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Synagogue Council of America, 1972-1977 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Tarbut Foundation, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 1971-1977 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Union of Councils for Soviet Jews, undated, 1971-1978 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Union of Orthodox Jewish Congregations of America, 1972-1975 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - United Israel Appeal, 1975-1978 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1971-1978 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - United Synagogue of America, 1971-1978 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - United Synagogue Youth, 1972-1977 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - United Zionist Revisionists, 1972-1974, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Women's American ORT (see also: ORT), 1972, 1975-1978 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Women's League for Conservative Judaism, 1974, 1977-1978 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - World Center for European Rabbis, 1972, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Workmen's Circle, 1972-1978 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - World Conference of Jewish Organizations, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - World Jewish Congress, 1971, 1973-1978 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - World Union for Progressive Judaism, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - World Zionist Organization, 1971-1978 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - World Zionist Organization, American Section, 1971-1978 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Writers and Artists for Peace in the Middle East, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - YIVO Institute, 1971, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Zamir Chorale Foundation, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Zionist Organization of America, 1971-1976, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Community Centers: Albany, 1972-1978 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Community Centers: Atlanta, 1971-1978 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Baltimore, 1971-1978 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Boston (see also: Action for Soviet Jewry, Mass.), 1971-1978 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, 1971-1978 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Cincinnati, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Cleveland, 1969, 1971-1978 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Columbus, Ohio, 1974-1975, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Dallas, 1971-1978 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Dayton, 1971, 1973, 1975, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Denver, 1971-1978 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Des Moines, 1972-1977 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Detroit, 1972-1978 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Hartford, 1971-1977 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Highland Park, NJ, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Hollywood, Fla., 1973-1979 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Honolulu, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Indianapolis, 1972-1977 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Kansas City, Mo., 1972-1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Louisville, 1972-1978 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Los Angeles, 1970-1972 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Los Angeles, 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Los Angeles, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Miami, 1971-1975 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Miami, 1976-1979 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Milwaukee, 1972, 1974-1975, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Minneapolis, 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Minneapolis, 1974-1978 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Nashville, 1972-1974 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - New Haven, 1971-1978 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - New Orleans, 1972-1978 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - New York Metropolitan Region (see also: L.I. Committee for Soviet Jewry), 1974-1975, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Norfolk, Va., 1972-1978 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Oakland, CA, 1972-1978 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Philadelphia, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Philadelphia, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Philadelphia, 1975-1978 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh, 1971-1978 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Portland, Oregon, 1973-1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Providence, R.I., 1971-1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Richmond, Va., 1973-1978 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Rochester, NY, 1974-1977 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - St. Louis, 1972-1978 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - San Francisco, 1972-1978 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Savannah, 1972-1977 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Seattle, Wash., 1973-1978 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Toledo, 1971, 1973, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Topeka, Kansas, 1977-1978 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Trenton, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Washington, DC, 1971-1974 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Washington, DC, 1975-1979 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Wilmington, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Alabama, 1972, 1975, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Arizona, 1973-1977 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Arkansas, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - California, 1974-1977 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut, 1971, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Florida, 1975-1978 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Illinois, 1973-1974 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Indiana, 1971, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Iowa, 1972, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Louisiana, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Maine, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Maryland, 1973, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts, 1973-1978 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Michigan, 1973, 1975, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Minnesota, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Nebraska, 1974-1977 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - New Jersey, 1971-1977 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - New Mexico, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - New York, 1971-1979 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - North Carolina (contains photographs), 1973-1974 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Ohio, 1971-1974 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Oklahoma, 1976-1978 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania, 1971, 1973-1974, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - South Carolina, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - South Dakota, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Tennessee, 1973, 1975, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Texas, 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Virginia, 1973, 1975, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Washington, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - West Virginia, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Wisconsin, 1974-1975, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 31)
- Part 1, Series V: U.S. Presidential, House and Senate Correspondence and Printed Materials, 1965-1978; Boxes 30-31.
  Contains correspondence with the US government and legislation bodies, organized chronologically and preserves the original order.
  - Nixon Administration (see also Visitors to the USSR), 1968-1972 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Nixon Administration, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Ford Administration, 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Carter Administration, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Commerce Department, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - State Department, 1965-1969 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - State Department, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - State Department, 1973-1976 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - State Department, 1977-1978 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - House of Representatives, 1965-1970 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - House of Representatives, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - House of Representatives, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - House of Representatives, 1973-1977 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Senate, 1968, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Senate, 1973-1977 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - McGovern, George, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1973-1974 (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Part 1, Series VI: Foreign Organizations Correspondence and Printed Material, undated, 1966-1979; Boxes 32-36.
  Arranged into two subseries.
  The Series includes correspondence with organizations outside of the U.S. which were involved in the Soviet Jewry Movement. The most of correspondence fall on Canada, England and Israel. Also included are publications by foreign Soviet Jewry Movement organizations. Organized alphabetically according to the name of organization.
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1966-1978; Boxes 32-33.
    - Australia. Executive Council; of Australian Jewry, 1967-1977 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Australia, 1966-1978 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Austria, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Belgium, 1974, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Bulgaria, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Canada, Canadian Committee for Soviet Jewry, 1975-1978 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Canada, Canadian Committee of Lawyers and Jurists, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Canada, Canadian Jewish Congress, 1967-1978 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Canada, Montreal Committee for Soviet Jewry, 1973-1975, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Canada, Montreal 35's, 1976-1977 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Canada, Toronto 35's, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Canada, Women for Soviet Jewry (Toronto), 1972-1974, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Canada, 1968-1974, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - England, Board of Deputies of British Jews, 1966-1975 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - England, Institute of Jewish Affairs, 1971, 1974-1975, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - England, Manchester Council for Soviet Jewry, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - England, National Council for Soviet Jewry, 1976-1978 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - England, 35's-Women's Campaign for Soviet Jewry, 1974-1978 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - England, 1968, 1972-1976 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - France, Bibliotheque Juive Contemporaine, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Israel, Government (by department), 1972-1973, 1975-1977 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Israel, Embassy in Washington, 1974-1978 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Israel, Action Committee of Newcomers, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Israel, Israel Aliyah Center, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Israel, Jewish Agency, 1971, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Israel, Israel Public Council for Soviet Jewry, 1971-1978 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Israel, Schroeter, Leonard, 1971-1973 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Israel, Shamir-Association of Jewish Religious Professionals, 1974-1978 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Israel, 1974-1975 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Italy, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Romania, 1975-1976 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - South America, 1968-1970, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Sweden, 1968, 1975-1976 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Switzerland, 1972, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Subseries B: Memoranda, Newsletters, Press releases, undated, 1967, 1969, 1971-1979; Boxes 34-36.
    - Australia, 1973, 1975, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Austria, undated, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Belgium, 1972, 1974, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Canada, Canadian Committee for Soviet Jewry, 1975, 1977-1978 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Canada, various organizations, 1976-1978 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - England, Board of Deputies for British Jews, 1969, 1972-1978 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - England, National Council for Soviet Jewry, 1976-1978 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - England. Jews in the USSR, bulletin, 1972-1975 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - England, 35's-Women's Campaign for Soviet Jewry, 1975-1978 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - England, World Union of Jewish Students, 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - England, various organizations, 1967, 1971-1978 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - France, Bibliotheque juive, 1972-1979 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - France, CRIF, 1972-1975 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - France, various organizations, 1974-1978 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Israel, Action Committee of Newcomers, 1971-1973 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Israel, Government, 1972-1976 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Israel, Israel Public Council for Soviet Jewry, 1972-1976 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Israel, SHAMIR, 1972, 1975-1976 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Israel, various organizations, 1972, 1975-1978 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Italy, 1972-1976 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - New Zealand, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Romania, 1977-1978 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - South America (incl. Central America), 1972-1978 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Sweden, undated, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Switzerland, 1971-1972, 1977-1978 (Box 36, Folder 6)
- Part 1, Series VII: NCSJ Activities, undated, 1966-1981; Boxes 37-67.
  The Series contains materials on projects, activities and events by ASCSJ and NCSJ on behalf of Soviet Jews. Among them are activities to publicize the plight of refuseniks and prisoners of conscience among the Western, first of all American, Jewish community (Freedom Bus, Candle for Soviet Jews, Adopt a Family etc.), petitions on behalf of Soviet Jews, rallies and demonstrations, briefing of visitors to the USSR and their trip reports upon return, correspondence regarding particular Soviet Jewish refuseniks, prisoners of conscience and émigrés.
  - Academicians (see also Correspondence, organizations -- Academic Committee on Soviet Jewry), 1972-1974 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Antisemitism, 1971-1972 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - August 12, 1952 -- Stalinist Terror, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - August 12, 1952 -- Anniversary of Execution of Jewish Intellectuals in the Soviet Union, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - August 12, 1952 -- The Night of the Murdered Poets, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - August 12, 1952 -- 20th Anniversary of the Murder of 24 Soviet Jewish Writers, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - August 12, 1952 -- anniversary, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - August 12, 1952 -- anniversary, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - August 12, 1952 -- anniversary, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - August 12, 1952 -- anniversary, 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Babi Yar commemoration, 1975-1976 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Black Community, 1972-1975 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Black Community -- Petition, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Books and Publications, 1973-1979 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Brezhnev, Leonid I. (see also visitors to the U.S.), 1974 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Campus Programming, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Chanukah, 1969, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Chanukah Demonstration, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Communications -- general, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Communications -- mail, 1972-1976 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Communications -- mail, returned, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Communications -- mail, Postal Data Collection Project, circa 1975 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Communications -- Parcels, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Communications -- Telephone, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Communications -- Telephone, Data, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Communications -- Telephone, Transcriptions, 1972-1978 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Communist Party USA -- Jews, undated, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Consular Treaty, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Détente, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Détente, summit, 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Dissent, Soviet, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Emergency Conference on Soviet Jewry, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Emigration from the USSR, general, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Emigration, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Emigration, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Emigration, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Emigration -- from the USSR to Israel, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Emigration -- Israel, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Emigration -- Israel, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Emigration -- Israel, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Emigration -- Israel, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Emigration -- Israel, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Emigration -- from the USSR to the US, 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Emigration -- U.S., 1973 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Emigration -- U.S., 1974 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Emigration -- U.S., 1975 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Emigration -- U.S., 1976 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Emigration -- U.S. Koch Bill, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Emigration -- U.S. Kennedy Bill, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Emigration -- U.S., 1977 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Emigration -- Dropouts (1 of 2), 1976 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Emigration -- Dropouts (2 of 2), 1976-1977 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Emigration -- Family Reunification Cases, A-E, circa 1976 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Emigration -- Family Reunification Cases, F-H, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Emigration -- Family Reunification Cases, I-L, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Emigration -- Family Reunification Cases, M-P, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Emigration -- Family Reunification Cases, Q-Z, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Emigration -- Family Reunion, 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Escape to the Sun film, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Eternal Light -- Torch of Cultural Freedom, 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Exhibit -- Tragedy of Soviet Jewry, 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - EXPO 1974 -- Spokane, Wash., 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Freedom Lights for Soviet Jewry, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Financial aid for Soviet Jews, undated, 1972-1974 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Freedom Bus, 1971-1972 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Human Rights, 1973-1977 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Human Rights -- Congressional Hearings, 1971-1974 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Human Rights Day for Soviet Jewry, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Helsinki Committee Meeting, 1977 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Helsinki -- Human Rights, 1973-1977 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Helsinki Day Press Conference, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Hunger Strike, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - European Jewish Conference on Soviet Jewry, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - World Conference on Soviet Jewry, 1970-1978 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Brussels Conference -- Delegates, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Brussels Conference -- correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Brussels Conference 1971 -- planning, 1970-1971 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Brussels Conference 1971 -- programs, resolutions (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Brussels Conference -- press reaction, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Brussels Conference -- letters from the USSR against, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Brussels Conference -- local agency delegates, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - London Meeting on Soviet Jewry-1972, 1971-1972 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Geneva Meeting -- 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - London Meeting, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Second World Conference of Jewish Communities on Soviet Jewry (Brussels II, 1976), 1975-1976 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Brussels II (1976) -- delegates (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Brussels II (1976) -- program (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Brussels II (1976) -- workshops, 1975-1976 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Brussels II (1976) -- press (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Brussels II (1976) -- resolutions (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Brussels II (1976) -- correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Brussels II (1976) -- follow up (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - International Legal Colloquium, London, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - International Seminar on Soviet Jewry, Kiryat Anavim, 1974-1975 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Moscow Symposium on Jewish Culture, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Absorption Conference on Soviet Jewish Immigration, 1976-1977 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - International declaration on Soviet Jewry, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - International Letter, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - International Day of recognition, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - International Women's Year, 1975 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Israel Mission (UJA/ NCSJ), 1974 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Leadership Conference, 1967 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Leadership Assembly, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Leadership Assembly, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Leadership Assembly, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Leadership Assembly, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Leadership Assembly, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Leningrad Jewish Club, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Lettoni, Jean (Yanco Leibovici), 1970-1971, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Levin, Yehudah Leib-birthday (see also visitors -- U.S., 1968 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - "Zalmen: or, the Madness of God," by Elie Wiesel, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Media contacts, 1970-1972 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Media contacts, 1973-1975 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Media contacts, 1976-1978 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Media -- WEVD Russia Reports, 1972-1975 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Media -- press, 1967-1968, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Moscow Sit-in, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Nationalities, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Norton, E. H., 1977 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Odessa cemetery, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Alexandrovich, Mikhail, 1972-1974 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Alexandrovich (Averbukh), Ruth, 1971-1972 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Gluzman, Rita, 1971-1972 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Kerbel, Moise, 1973 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Khenkin, Kirill, 1973-1974 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Kochubiyevsky, Boris, 1972 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Kogan, Boris, 1972-1973 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Levich, Benyamin and Tanya, undated (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Libman, Bluma and Julia, 1972 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Makhlis, Leonid, 1972 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Mandelzveig, Viktor, 1973-1974 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Mash, Vladimir, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Model, Lev, 1973-1974 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Panov (Shulman), Valery, 1972-1973 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Panov (Shulman), Valery and Galina, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Polsky, Viktor, 1974-1975 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Radomislsky, Mikhail, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Segal, Dmitrii, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Sevela, Efraim (Drabkin, Efim), 1972 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Shapiro, Beniamin, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Shkolnik, Feiga, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Shapiro, Gavriel (Silver, Judy), 1972 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Shepshelovich, Mikhail, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Stiglitz, Michael, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Teitelbaum, Daniel, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Voloshin, Arkady, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Olim -- A (Abramovich, Ass, Alter, Aronson et al.), 1971-1978 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Olim -- B (Banchik, Barshai, Barsky, Belfor et al.), 1972-1978 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Olim -- C-E, 1972-1977 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Olim -- F, 1972-1977 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Olim -- G, 1974-1977 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Olim -- I-K, 1972-1979 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Olim -- L, 1972-1977 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Olim -- P, 1973-1977 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Olim -- M-O, 1972-1977 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Olim -- R, 1972-1978 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Olim -- S, 1972-1979 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Olim -- T-Z, 1973-1977 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Olim -- aid-resettlement, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Olim -- correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Olympics (Moscow 1980), 1978-1979 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Oral History Project, 1976-1977 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Organizations -- Chamah, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Organizations -- Shomer Achi, 1977-1978 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Orphans of the Exodus Vigil, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Panovs' Tribute, 1973-1975 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - "Parasitism" cases, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Passover Vigil for Soviet Jewry, 1969-1978 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Passover -- Matzah of Oppression, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Passover -- Matzah of Hope, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Passover -- Matzah of Hope, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Passover -- Matzah of Hope, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Passover -- Matzah of Hope, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Passover -- Matzah of Hope, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Passover -- Matzah of Hope, 1972-1978 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Penson Exhibition, 1972-1975 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Penson Exhibition, 1972-1975 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Petition campaign, 1975-1976 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Poster campaign, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)